Dmitry Beskov

Frontend developer

Tbilisi, Georgia | dmitry.beskov@outlook.com | besdar.github.io

Summary

I'm an experienced React frontend developer. During my work I often make suggestions to a project's codebase to make the team's daily work more effective, more fun and/or easier. I also try to fix code issues that I see on a regular basis. I really love what I do and I want to continue to grow in the frontend to create something great and special.

Work experience

JettyCloud (UCaaS) 2022 - 2024

Senior Software Developer

- Worked simultaneously in more than 4 teams (around 30 people) on more than 3 projects and received only positive feedbacks from my colleagues during a performance review process
- Was noticed as one of the fastest employees in the team
- Was the author of more than 50 technical tasks designed to improve the performance and quality of the code
- Was involved in the recruitment process and as a result developed a technical interviewing knowledge base for all roles across the company, which improved our interviewing process
- Created a Chrome extension tool to generate test accounts, which made the daily work of both QA engineers and developers much easier

In this role, I was usually responsible for the creating, updating and maintenaning various sub-modules for customer account pages and internal administration pages.

Stack: TS, React&Redux, Java&Kotlin, GraphQL

Foxford (EdTech) | 2021 - 2022

Frontend developer

- Started a code review process for the team, was an organizer of weekly frontend meetings
- Added many new rules to the ESLint to make it stricter in the project, added Stylelint, created code style guides for the team. As a result, the development process became faster and our product became more stable
- Enchanced the Rollup building script and configuration to deliver less data to our customers: added code splitting for production builds, CSS modules support, source maps and much more
- Improved our Lighthouse perfomance and SEO metrics by 30%, and started an epic task of moving from a 3rd party website builder to React template based development

Practically was a team leader (4 developers), worked a lot with HTML&CSS and performed managerial activities like teamwork process optimization on various development stages

Stack: JS&Flow, JQuery, HTML&CSS, React&Effector, NodeJS

Adsterra (AdTech) 2020 - 2021

Frontend developer

- Was noticed as one of the fastest employees in our department
- Offered JS linter and Styleint improvements and integration techniques, minification of JS and CSS; took active part in writing our frontend style guide; played a significant role in the refactoring process of our legacy code to modern syntax
- Successfully and confidently worked with PHP and PostgreSQL backends when the company was understaffed and was needed a backend boost
- Was praised for being self-sufficient during the onboarding process

Main areas of work were development of the advertising JS scripts, internal admin tools and the company's client account pages. Formerly I worked in another company, but for Adsterra's projects

Stack: JS, JQuery, HTML&CSS, PHP, PostgreSQL, React&Redux, Vue

Education

Saint Petersburg State Electrotechnical University 2014 - 2018

Communication Technologies and Communication Systems

Faculty of Radio Engineering and Telecommunications